<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Nick on Computing: Posts tagged Dad</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/tags/Dad/index.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/tags/Dad/index.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Nicholas McAvoy</name>
        <email>nicholas.mcavoy@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2014-07-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Eleven Years' Bereavement</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/nick/posts/2014/07/26/eleven-years-bereavement/" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/nick/posts/2014/07/26/eleven-years-bereavement/</id>
    <published>2014-07-26T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
  <header>
    <h1 class="entry-title">
      <a href="/nick/posts/2014/07/26/eleven-years-bereavement/">Eleven Years' Bereavement</a>
    </h1>
    <div class="meta">
      <time datetime="2014-07-26" pubdate data-updated="true">26 July 2014</time>
      <div class="tags"><a href="/tags/Dad/index.html">Dad</a></div>
    </div>
  </header>

  <p>My dad died eleven years ago yesterday. At his funeral a week later I read the following:</p>
<!-- MORE -->

<pre class="prose">
Eric McAvoy’s contributions to the world without a doubt consist of those he made as husband, father, and brother, not those he made as computer programmer, customer service rep, or salesman. It’s true. My father’s largest successes cannot be measured by any definable quantity, such as money or property. They are seen in the impact he made on the lives of those he loved, and of those who loved him. No one will remember the Eric McAvoy that answered phones; many will remember the Eric McAvoy that helped raise and nurture a family. 

I remember Dad for many things. He loved animals, as evidenced by the cats, dogs, rabbits, hamsters, fish, parakeets, and even chickens we have kept as pets over the years. History fascinated him, from the Revolutionary and Civil Wars to antiques or anything he dug up metal detecting. He was car mechanic, landscaper, plumber, and carpenter in one. Dad loved classical music, especially some good solid Beethoven. He rose and fell every year with the trends of the Phillies and Eagles. A good western, whether an Elmer Kelton novel or a John Wayne movie. Drives in the country and the scent of cow manure. Scrapple, garden tomatoes, or anything my mom cooked. These were all things that Dad loved. He baked warm bread for cold winter evenings and made chocolate syrup for hot summer afternoons.

However, while all of these things describe my father, they only serve to create a sketch of him rather than an accurate portrait. If one trait characterized him above all others, it was his absolute love for his wife and children. Dad’s altruistic devotion for us was unceasing and limitless in depth, displayed in daily life through actions large and small. For years Dad worked the night shift while also attending college, forced to live regularly on three or four hours of sleep and almost no time for leisure. He would always give the larger half of a sandwich or the better seat at an event. When we didn’t have a second car, he walked to the bus stop. Even weakened and in great pain from his illness, Dad still took care of the house, the lawn, the cars, and the three of us. His love defined him and shaped all he did.

Now, though my father has gone, the results of his actions remain. No one in attendance today has gone untouched by his life. We are left to allow his influence to continue by following the example he set forth in his time on Earth. Let his quiet strength and compassion give rise to the same within yourselves.  
</pre>

<p>I am filled with sorrow for the father who labored so much and who died before he could reap the best fruits of so much love.</p>
</article>

]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Seeing Dad</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/nick/posts/2014/02/04/seeing-dad/" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/nick/posts/2014/02/04/seeing-dad/</id>
    <published>2014-02-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
  <header>
    <h1 class="entry-title">
      <a href="/nick/posts/2014/02/04/seeing-dad/">Seeing Dad</a>
    </h1>
    <div class="meta">
      <time datetime="2014-02-04" pubdate data-updated="true"> 4 February 2014</time>
      <div class="tags"><a href="/tags/dreams/index.html">dreams</a> | <a href="/tags/Dad/index.html">Dad</a></div>
    </div>
  </header>

  <p>A recurring motif in dreams in which my father appears is that I embrace him.</p>
<p>The embrace is one part joy at having him wth me again and one part fear of losing him again.</p>
<p>Ten years after his death I am glad that I still have these dreams. These emotions ought not be buried beneath forgetfulness. And the dreams remind me to pray that they come true.</p>
</article>

]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
