<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Nick on Computing: Posts tagged dreams</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/tags/dreams/index.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/blog" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/tags/dreams/index.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Nicholas McAvoy</name>
        <email>nicholas.mcavoy@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2014-01-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Alien Grace</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/nick/posts/2014/01/27/alien-grace/" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/nick/posts/2014/01/27/alien-grace/</id>
    <published>2014-01-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-01-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
  <header>
    <h1 class="entry-title">
      <a href="/nick/posts/2014/01/27/alien-grace/">Alien Grace</a>
    </h1>
    <div class="meta">
      <time datetime="2014-01-27" pubdate data-updated="true">27 January 2014</time>
      <div class="tags"><a href="/tags/dreams/index.html">dreams</a></div>
    </div>
  </header>

  <p>I had a beautiful dream last night.</p>
<p>The whole world was anxious about something in outer space that was headed for Earth. It was visible in the night sky as a dark green star moving toward the zenith. We didn’t know what it was but we all remembered what happened to the dinosaurs.</p>
<p>When it got close, something from Earth went up and met it. Green turned to blue. I was relieved to infer that it would not be colliding with us, but in the next moment I realized the fallout from that interaction would be reaching us momentarily and for all I knew we were still going to get it.</p>
<p>I called my mom to warn her to take cover and I braced myself inside a narrow closet. I feared for all of the people who would be out in the open, unaware of the danger we still faced. Then the moment arrived.</p>
<!-- MORE -->

<p>We were not annihilated. In fact, looking out the window, the whole world had been transformed. Though it remained deep night, all plants were aglow with luminescent pinpricks of all colors. It was like a natural Christmas display, but still with the softness of night.</p>
<p>We had feared not unwisely that the unknown celestial event would destroy us. But whoever sent it came to bless us in a way more wonderful than we could have imagined.</p>
<p>Usually only bad dreams wake you. But this one woke me right up.</p>
</article>

]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
