<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Nick on Computing: Posts tagged all peoples</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/tags/all%20peoples/index.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/tags/all%20peoples/index.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Nicholas McAvoy</name>
        <email>nicholas.mcavoy@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2014-07-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Welcoming the Stranger</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/yhwh/posts/2014/07/19/welcoming-the-stranger/" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/yhwh/posts/2014/07/19/welcoming-the-stranger/</id>
    <published>2014-07-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
  <header>
    <h1 class="entry-title">
      <a href="/yhwh/posts/2014/07/19/welcoming-the-stranger/">Welcoming the Stranger</a>
    </h1>
    <div class="meta">
      <time datetime="2014-07-19" pubdate data-updated="true">19 July 2014</time>
      <div class="tags"><a href="/tags/all%20peoples/index.html">all peoples</a></div>
    </div>
  </header>

  <p>I was riding my bike home this evening past the Penn campus when I saw three people struggling around a campus map. It was starting to get dark and they were using their phones to try and illuminate the map. Like usual in this kind of situation, I pulled over to ask if I could help them find their way.</p>
<!-- MORE -->

<p>I was a little puzzled at first because they looked perfectly plausibly like Penn students: Asian, two men and a woman, in casual summer dress, just like thousands of people at Penn. But when I asked if they needed help finding something they didn’t understand me fully at first. At that point it was clear they were probably visiting foreigners.</p>
<p>As it turned out I had never heard of the building they were searching for, so instead of simply pointing them on their way I got out my phone and searched with them. In the meantime I noticed they were speaking Korean to one another.</p>
<p>“You guys from Korea?” I asked.</p>
<p>They seemed quite surprised. “Yes. How do you know?” the woman asked.</p>
<p>“You’re speaking Korean.”</p>
<p>I played it off like it was normal for an American to distinguish Korean from other Asian languages. It’s not, of course. Neither did I regale them with stories of studying Korean or visiting Korea.</p>
<p>Eventually I did find the building’s location and I gave them clear directions. I asked a bit about their visit and wished them a sincere welcome and a good stay here in Philadephia.</p>
<p>It was a very affirming experience for me. It reminded me something of why I started studying Korean to begin with. In most of the U.S. east Asian people are all assumed to be Chinese, or perhaps Japanese. To be able to offer those visitors a welcome rooted in some measure of understanding made a real difference in our interaction, and things like that go a long way toward a visitor’s perception of a place.</p>
<p>God welcomes us as strangers into his family. Extending that welcome to others is part of his call to us and a gift. I hope this little experience of doing so foreshadows more chances to do so in bigger ways.</p>
</article>

]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
