<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Nick on Computing: blog</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/nick/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/blog" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/nick/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Nicholas McAvoy</name>
        <email>nicholas.mcavoy@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2014-02-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>The Rider And His Mount</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/nick/posts/2014/02/02/the-rider-and-his-mount/" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/nick/posts/2014/02/02/the-rider-and-his-mount/</id>
    <published>2014-02-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
  <header>
    <h1 class="entry-title">
      <a href="/nick/posts/2014/02/02/the-rider-and-his-mount/">The Rider And His Mount</a>
    </h1>
    <div class="meta">
      <time datetime="2014-02-02" pubdate data-updated="true"> 2 February 2014</time>
      <div class="tags"><a href="/tags/transportation/">transportation</a></div>
    </div>
  </header>

  <p>Biycycles are inanimate, but there remains a deep affection of the rider for his mount. This affection can extend even to identification.</p>
<p>I took my bike to the bike shop this weekend and it was cathartic. The bike was already in a shop, but I took it to Via Bicycle where they were more likely to have a matching fork in the event a replacement was necessary. To myself I jokingly called the move a “patient transfer.”</p>
<p>The owner of Via Bicycle reintroduced himself as Curtis, but with a moustache and a manner with a crowd of customers like his no reintroduction was necessary. Curtis lives up to this image, too; it’s not an exaggeratin to call him a bicycle sage.</p>
<p>Curtis put my bike on a stand and told me about its damage, his eyes finding in a minute what others’ instruments had missed. This after the car accident that put me out of commission for almost five months.</p>
<!-- MORE -->

<p>At first glance the bike was okay. But Curtis had me crouch a bit and look at the top tube at eye level. Yup, now that I looked at it, it definitely bent downward near the front. Not so much the integrity was threatened, but enough to notice, and matter.</p>
<p>Come to look at it, the handlebars were bent, too. The brake lever was way off line, the headset worse for the wear. The scuffs on the cork tape revealed an intimate acquaintance with the road.</p>
<p>There was considerably more damage than met the casual eye. There is an identification of the rider with his mount.</p>
</article>

]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Lists</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/nick/posts/2014/02/01/lists/" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/nick/posts/2014/02/01/lists/</id>
    <published>2014-02-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
  <header>
    <h1 class="entry-title">
      <a href="/nick/posts/2014/02/01/lists/">Lists</a>
    </h1>
    <div class="meta">
      <time datetime="2014-02-01" pubdate data-updated="true"> 1 February 2014</time>
      <div class="tags"><a href="/tags/organization/">organization</a></div>
    </div>
  </header>

  <p>I am not very good at getting chores done.</p>
<p>I find the simple act of making a list of tasks greatly increases the likelihood that I will do them. I can have a task in my mind for weeks without doing it, even if it is as simple as a phone call. Yet somehow when I make the list something clicks and I start knocking off items.</p>
<p>Who knew?</p>
</article>

]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Alien Grace</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/nick/posts/2014/01/27/alien-grace/" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/nick/posts/2014/01/27/alien-grace/</id>
    <published>2014-01-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-01-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
  <header>
    <h1 class="entry-title">
      <a href="/nick/posts/2014/01/27/alien-grace/">Alien Grace</a>
    </h1>
    <div class="meta">
      <time datetime="2014-01-27" pubdate data-updated="true">27 January 2014</time>
      <div class="tags"><a href="/tags/dreams/">dreams</a></div>
    </div>
  </header>

  <p>I had a beautiful dream last night.</p>
<p>The whole world was anxious about something in outer space that was headed for Earth. It was visible in the night sky as a dark green star moving toward the zenith. We didn’t know what it was but we all remembered what happened to the dinosaurs.</p>
<p>When it got close, something from Earth went up and met it. Green turned to blue. I was relieved to infer that it would not be colliding with us, but in the next moment I realized the fallout from that interaction would be reaching us momentarily and for all I knew we were still going to get it.</p>
<p>I called my mom to warn her to take cover and I braced myself inside a narrow closet. I feared for all of the people who would be out in the open, unaware of the danger we still faced. Then the moment arrived.</p>
<!-- MORE -->

<p>We were not annihilated. In fact, looking out the window, the whole world had been transformed. Though it remained deep night, all plants were aglow with luminescent pinpricks of all colors. It was like a natural Christmas display, but still with the softness of night.</p>
<p>We had feared not unwisely that the unknown celestial event would destroy us. But whoever sent it came to bless us in a way more wonderful than we could have imagined.</p>
<p>Usually only bad dreams wake you. But this one woke me right up.</p>
</article>

]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
