<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Nick on Computing: Posts tagged church</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/tags/church/index.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/tags/church/index.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Nicholas McAvoy</name>
        <email>nicholas.mcavoy@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2014-03-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Our First and Our Best</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/yhwh/posts/2014/03/03/our-first-and-our-best/" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/yhwh/posts/2014/03/03/our-first-and-our-best/</id>
    <published>2014-03-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
  <header>
    <h1 class="entry-title">
      <a href="/yhwh/posts/2014/03/03/our-first-and-our-best/">Our First and Our Best</a>
    </h1>
    <div class="meta">
      <time datetime="2014-03-03" pubdate data-updated="true"> 3 March 2014</time>
      <div class="tags"><a href="/tags/church/index.html">church</a></div>
    </div>
  </header>

  <p>I got a couple of lessons from church on a trip to New York last weekend.</p>
<p>The first was the reenforcement of something I first learned from my friend Youmie. It might be difficult to understand. I was amazed to learn from her in 2009 that she had missed church only a handful of times in her life. Missing church just wasn’t much of an option for her.</p>
<p>What is probably hard to understand about this attitude is that this constant attendance was linked neither to avoiding guilt for missing church nor to pride in having gleaming attendance. It was challenging to me because missing a particular Sunday had never seemed like a very big deal to me. Since that conversation I have tried to take on this outlook myself.</p>
<p>Doing so was a bit of a challenge yesterday. The reason I was in New York to begin with was for <a href="http://nescala.org">a conference</a> that I had helped organize and a morning of which I would hate to miss. Moreover, my absence would be noticed and I would have to explain that I was going to church, which can feel awkward around a bunch of people who by and large are not religious.</p>
<p>Still, I thought I had better stick to my guns. I went with my friends Phil and Ava to <a href="http://emmanuelnyc.org">Emmanuel Presbyterian Church</a> on the Upper West Side. And I am so glad that I did.</p>
<!-- MORE -->

<p>While I did miss talks I would have liked to see, the Holy Spirit met me at the church service in a big way. This happened in a few ways, but I would like to focus on one.</p>
<p>The offertory. Wow. A member of the church played an etude by Chopin. This was an entirely different level than I had ever conceived of. My own church is blessed with excellent musicians, but I confess that I think of the music played during the offertory as not very much more than background music, without which silence during the passing of collection plates might be awkward.</p>
<p>But this was no mere offertory. It was itself an offering. This was a concert-quality performance by a concert-quality musician. It was not timed to conclude once the monetary offerings had been collected. It slayed and I nearly cried.</p>
<p>When the performance ended, no one clapped. The artist returned to her seat in silence, depths of emotion I could not read playing across her face.</p>
<p>I was convicted that this was as much an offering as if we had taken a choice bull to the altar and slain it on the spot. What a gift it was, I realized, to be able to give one’s first and one’s best to the Lord. Like my decision to go to church that morning, this was not a burden but the loosing of one.</p>
<p>I wondered how we could take this principle farther into the reaches of our lives. I imagined taking the first pint from one of the batches of beer we brew for our church parties and pouring it out on the ground. I imagined owning a restaurant and giving the first hour’s service to such as live in shelters. I imagined working hard on Saturdays for software to benefit churches.</p>
<p>Such are not ways to fool or bargain God into giving us what we really want. Rather they are a means to know him, to come to want him most, which is our end.</p>
<p>Lord, may I ever remember the beauty of the Chopin offering. May we know the joy of offering you our first and our best.</p>
</article>

]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
