<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Nick on Computing: Posts tagged cooking</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/tags/cooking/index.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/tags/cooking/index.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Nicholas McAvoy</name>
        <email>nicholas.mcavoy@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2014-05-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Thursday Dinner</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/food/posts/2014/05/22/thursday-dinner/" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/food/posts/2014/05/22/thursday-dinner/</id>
    <published>2014-05-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
  <header>
    <h1 class="entry-title">
      <a href="/food/posts/2014/05/22/thursday-dinner/">Thursday Dinner</a>
    </h1>
    <div class="meta">
      <time datetime="2014-05-22" pubdate data-updated="true">22 May 2014</time>
      <div class="tags"><a href="/tags/cooking/index.html">cooking</a></div>
    </div>
  </header>

  <p>Now that was the way it is supposed to be.</p>
<p>At 8:35 I looked at the clock and sighed a contented sigh. Two hours earlier I had left work. Two hours had been enough time to catch the train, ride my bike home, and cook and eat a satisfying meal despite having no prior plan.</p>
<!-- MORE -->

<p>That’s what my CSA is supposed to do for me. CSA stands for community-supported agriculture. It’s basically a vegetable subscription. I sign up for a season and every week I pick up a box of goods from farms in Lancaster County. Everything is fresh and organic and, Pennsylvania being the bounteous land that it is, there is a lot of variety.</p>
<p>Without the CSA I likely would have eaten out somewhere. But with it, even though I had given no thought to Thursday dinner before Thursday evening I had plenty to work with without needing to stop at the store. I ended up cooking up some CSA baby red Russian kale and shiitake mushrooms along with some onion, garlic, and lemon I had on hand. I served it on thin toasted slices of the sourdough bread I make every week. It hit the spot!</p>
<p>And so I achieved something very rare for me: a delicious, satisfying meal that did not take much time, effort, or planning. After finishing I had so much time left over I decided to write a blog post.</p>
</article>

]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
