<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Nick on Computing: Posts tagged Bible study</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/tags/Bible%20study/index.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/blog" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/tags/Bible%20study/index.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Nicholas McAvoy</name>
        <email>nicholas.mcavoy@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2014-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>"...that they might live in the spirit the way God does."</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/yhwh/posts/2014/02/13/that-they-might-live-in-the-spirit-the-way-god-does/" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/blog/yhwh/posts/2014/02/13/that-they-might-live-in-the-spirit-the-way-god-does/</id>
    <published>2014-02-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
  <header>
    <h1 class="entry-title">
      <a href="/yhwh/posts/2014/02/13/that-they-might-live-in-the-spirit-the-way-god-does/">"...that they might live in the spirit the way God does."</a>
    </h1>
    <div class="meta">
      <time datetime="2014-02-13" pubdate data-updated="true">13 February 2014</time>
      <div class="tags"><a href="/tags/Bible%20study/index.html">Bible study</a></div>
    </div>
  </header>

  <p>At last night’s community group we studied <a href="http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=1+peter+4%3A1-11&amp;version=ESV">1 Peter 4:1-11</a>. Verse 6 stuck out to me most:</p>
<pre><code>For this is why the gospel was preached even to those who are dead, that though judged in the flesh the way people are, they might live in the spirit the way God does.</code></pre>
<p>The context is the change in the lives of Christians, that rather than being ruled by the passions of their sinful nature (the flesh), they be ruled by Jesus’s way of living which included suffering and dying.</p>
<!-- MORE -->

<p>We discussed a few reasons for Christians to take up the painful life of dying to the passions that used to rule their lives. One reason Peter mentions explicitly is that such deeds will one day be judged before God. We all agreed that fear of retribution may be the least noble reason for good works, but it could still be a motivating force. Another reason we inferred from the text is that there is no escape from suffering. The fruits of living after the pattern of their former lives are likewise suffering and death. If suffering and death are to be had either way, we might as well suffer for good rather than for our own selfish passions. Peter himself makes this point earlier in his letter.</p>
<p>But the reason that was most provocative for me, and most difficult to imagine, was the final clause in verse 6, the promise of living “in the spirit the way God does.” Lately I have become the more aware of how tenuous life in the flesh is. If we enjoy prosperity and health in our lives, it can come to an end any day, and it is guaranteed to come to an end before too long. Over our lives looms the judgment we will receive after they end, the good account we must and cannot give.</p>
<p>Contrast that to the kind of life God enjoys: utterly effortless and self-consistent, unshakeable, joyous. Peter promises that this is the kind of life on the other end of suffering for the Gospel. More than a simple reward for doing good, it is nothing less than what he elsewhere calls to “partake of the divine nature.” God means not only to bless man as man, but also to elevate man with the mantle of divinity.</p>
<p>Wow. I’ll suffer for that.</p>
</article>

]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
