<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Nick on Computing: Posts tagged theology</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/tags/theology/index.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/tags/theology/index.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Nicholas McAvoy</name>
        <email>nicholas.mcavoy@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2014-01-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>The Bondage of the Will</title>
    <link href="http://nickmcavoy.com/yhwh/posts/2014/01/30/the-bondage-of-the-will/" />
    <id>http://nickmcavoy.com/yhwh/posts/2014/01/30/the-bondage-of-the-will/</id>
    <published>2014-01-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-01-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
  <header>
    <h1 class="entry-title">
      <a href="/yhwh/posts/2014/01/30/the-bondage-of-the-will/">The Bondage of the Will</a>
    </h1>
    <div class="meta">
      <time datetime="2014-01-30" pubdate data-updated="true">30 January 2014</time>
      <div class="tags"><a href="/tags/theology/index.html">theology</a></div>
    </div>
  </header>

  <p>Why not start this blog with some heavy lifting?</p>
<p>A prominent question in Christian theology is that of free will. One of the hardest things to believe in Christianity is that not everyone will be saved; some portion of humanity will receive everlasting life and some portion of humanity will receive everlasting death.</p>
<p>But just what determines who is in what camp? Does God mostly leave it up to people individually? Or does he choose ahead of time? Two things that seem to be at stake are human responsibility and divine sovereignty. If the choice is not up to people, then it can be difficult to see how they could be held responsible for failing to choose life. But if the choice is left to people, then it could seem that God is powerless to save those he would like to but who choose otherwise.</p>
<p>The answer from Scripture seems to be something of a paradox. The Bible shamelessly upholds that God bestows his salvation on those and only those whom he chooses, and it also shamelessly urges all to repent and call upon the name of the <span class="yhwh">Lord</span> for salvation.</p>
<p>From my perspective, our wills are neither as enslaved as we fear nor as free as we wish.</p>
<!-- MORE -->

<p>First, we are not automatons. Choice and consciousness are not illusions. (Proof is left as an exercise to the reader.) Christian argument against free will is not mostly of the sort that denies agency.</p>
<p>It is not that we have no will. Rather it is that our will is constrained by sin. The best analogy I can come up with is that of a shark swimming in the ocean. The shark is free to swim wherever it wills, and so it does. But the shark is incapable of standing up on a beach and walking on dry land. No one is stopping it per se, but no one needs to; the shark lacks the innate ability to walk.</p>
<p>Now, I do find Scripture persuasive on this matter, as well as the arguments of the likes of Martin Luther. But what persuades me most about the bondage of the will and the reason I have been thinking about it is that my own life constantly reinforces the idea.</p>
<p>It feels a bit silly to say this, but I experience the bondage of my will most palpably with my chronic lateness. I am late to almost everything I go to, and for no good reason. As a single and unencumbered man there is no other person who could make me late. Nor is it that I do not care about being on time. I actually hate being late and am ashamed of my lateness.</p>
<p>Yet it seems that one of the particular ways that I am fallen is that I am intrinsically incapable of punctuality. In a sense my mornings are like the movie Groundhog Day. Each has its own unique script, yet regardless of the details each converges on the same result.</p>
<p>My will is free. And every day my will chooses to be late. Wrap your mind around that and you will understand what is meant by the bondage of the will.</p>
<p>In the meantime, Holy Spirit, fill me up and take away my lateness.</p>
</article>

]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
